<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Observer on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/tags/observer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Observer on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 14:01:19 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/tags/observer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GUI Showdown</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2022/02/11/gui-showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2022/02/11/gui-showdown/</guid>
      <description>Andy&amp;rsquo;s GUI Showdown - The same application, implemented in various ways - which is better, cleaner, more understandable etc?&#xA;Like the TodoMVC &amp;ldquo;Rosetta Stone&amp;rdquo; project, but uses a different example application, and includes Python as well as Javascript implementations.&#xA;This project was originally intended to see if an ECS (Entity Component System), which is commonly used in building games, could be used to implement a &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; GUI application.&#xA;Five Javascript implementations: Live Demo of all Javascript implementations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TodoMVC implemented using traditional OO, Controllers and Events</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2020/05/18/todomvc-implemented-using-traditional-oo-controllers-and-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2020/05/18/todomvc-implemented-using-traditional-oo-controllers-and-events/</guid>
      <description>TodoMVC implemented in a classic Object Oriented way.&#xA;TodoMVC is a long standing web project showing how a ToDo app can be built in numerous frameworks.&#xA;The classic Javascript TodoMVC app implemented without a framework, using plain Object Oriented programming + a traditional MVC design pattern. Distinct, mediating Controller objects are the key to this implementation.&#xA;Running demo here.&#xA;See my full article on Medium here.&#xA;See also this GitHub repo by Marc Grabanski which shows us how to built TodoMVC in vanilla JS in 2022 (no classes are used in this version).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVC-App Architectural Pattern</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/patterns/mvca-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/patterns/mvca-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article describes the &amp;ldquo;MVC-App Architectural Pattern&amp;rdquo; which you can use to design your software applications, when you need to support a GUI. It is not a framework, it is a small set of principles which let you build sane, modular GUIs in any language, using any off the shelf UI components.&#xA;For the original, deprecated, MGM pattern which initially inspired this &amp;ldquo;MVC-App Pattern&amp;rdquo; pattern, see MGM pattern&#xA;TodoMVC-OO This is the classic Javascript TodoMVC app implemented without a framework 😄, simply using plain Object Oriented programming + a traditional MVC design pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring to PureMVC</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2009/04/01/refactoring-to-puremvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2009/04/01/refactoring-to-puremvc/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to refactor an existing architecture to the PureMVC architecture. Your application requires that you display &amp;lsquo;model&amp;rsquo; data in some sort of UI &amp;lsquo;view&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;Introduction MVC Architectural Pattern I have long been fascinated by the MVC (Model View Controller) architectural pattern, first conceived in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s. What it promises, to those who can fathom its mysteries, is an orderly way of organising your application architecture. You define a de-coupled domain/business model that is oblivious to any GUI that might be displaying it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PureMVC</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2009/03/01/puremvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2009/03/01/puremvc/</guid>
      <description>PureMVC - Architectural Pattern incl. a minimal wxPython example.&#xA;Understanding PureMVC can be hard, even though it is a relatively simple framework. That&amp;rsquo;s why a minimal example can help. Here is one I created for wxPython and Python users. This will run fine on windows, mac and linux. Install the PureMVC python port and wxPython (which is already present on Mac 10.5) and you should be able to run it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
