<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libraries &amp; Tools on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Libraries &amp; Tools on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dedent for Dart</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/dedent-dart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/dedent-dart/</guid>
      <description>Dedent for Dart Dedent - Remove any common leading whitespace from every line in text. Ported from Python.&#xA;https://pub.dev/packages/dedent</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron-Flask App Generator</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/electron-flask-app-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/electron-flask-app-gen/</guid>
      <description>Electron-Flask App Generator Yoeman project generator to create an Electron app running a Flask server inside itself. Deployable via PyInstaller and Electron Forge packager.&#xA;Create an Electron App project that auto-starts a Flask server the electron app can call for services. Deployable as a single App that users can double click on and run.&#xA;https://github.com/abulka/generator-electron-flask&#xA;_-----_ ╭──────────────────────────╮ | | │ Welcome to the amazing │ |--(o)--| │ generator-electron-flask │ `---------´ │ generator!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EuroPi - Trigger to Gate</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-trigger-to-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-trigger-to-gate/</guid>
      <description>Trigger to Gate Script for EuroPi This script allows you to convert trigger into a gate signal.&#xA;This is a common requirement in Eurorack modular synthesizers, where some modules require a gate signal to trigger an event, rather than a trigger signal.&#xA;See this explanation on the difference between gates and triggers.&#xA;I originally wrote this script because my 2hp MIDI module clock was outputting 6ms triggers, which are too short to inter-operate with most of my Eurorack modules, which require longer gates e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EuroPi - Andy&#39;s Utility Classes</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-script-utils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-script-utils/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My Trigger to Gate script for EuroPi uses some utility functions I developed, that might be useful for other EuroPi scripts:&#xA;KnobWithHysteresis KnobWithPassThrough Scheduler Rather than each EuroPi script inventing its own hyseresis mitigation and knob pass-through logic etc., these utility classes can be used by any EuroPi script that needs them.&#xA;You can install them into the lib/contrib/experimental directory of the EuroPi software, or in a separate lib/contrib/utils directory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Presenter</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/image-presenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/image-presenter/</guid>
      <description>Image Presenter An image presentation tool, where you can click and zoom into various parts of a single image.&#xA;Relevant text notes associated with each sub-area would appear when zoomed in. Arrow keys/buttons allow you to step through a narrated sequence of zooms, so that you get can be carefully guided through an art image, or diagram.&#xA;Two demo prototype versions, using different underlying technologies:&#xA;https://atug.com/image_presenter/layerjs/ https://atug.com/image_presenter/zoomooz/ Source code currently unreleased.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebook Tools</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/jupyter-notebook-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/jupyter-notebook-tools/</guid>
      <description>Jupyter Notebook Tools A way of implementing complex calculators incl. scrolling text area UI widgets within Jupyter &amp;amp; Colaboratory Notebooks.&#xA;Scrolling Textareas for Jupyter Notebooks Scrolling Textareas in a Python Jupyter Notebook, allows building a kind of &amp;ldquo;Calculator Playground&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Various Jupyter Notebooks at https://bitbucket.org/abulka/jupyter_play/src/master/ (private)&#xA;Gist of the scrolling textarea technique: https://gist.github.com/abulka/3043e8a4d78d2e26f872542524a0aa3e (public)&#xA;Google Colaboratory A way of implementing UI scrolling regions within Google Colaboratory Notebooks. Google Colaboratory, or &amp;ldquo;Colab&amp;rdquo; for short, is a version of Jupyter Notebooks, and allows you to write and execute Python in your browser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relationship Manager for Python 3</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/relationship-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/relationship-manager/</guid>
      <description>Relationship Manager A lightweight Object Database (no SQL used) class for Python 3&#xA;https://pypi.org/project/relationship-manager/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snippet Creator</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippet-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippet-creator/</guid>
      <description>Snippet Creator This Visual Studio Code extension helps to automate snippet creation. Select the code you want to create snippet from and use command Create Snippet from the command palette or your custom keybind.&#xA;https://github.com/abulka/vscode-snippet-creator</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snippets Explorer</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippets-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippets-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Snippets Explorer Visual Studio Code extension which displays all available language snippets in a TreeView&#xA;https://github.com/abulka/vscode-snippets-explorer</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
