<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refactoring on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/tags/refactoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refactoring on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 14:01:19 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/tags/refactoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MVC-App Architectural Pattern</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/patterns/mvca-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/patterns/mvca-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article describes the &amp;ldquo;MVC-App Architectural Pattern&amp;rdquo; which you can use to design your software applications, when you need to support a GUI. It is not a framework, it is a small set of principles which let you build sane, modular GUIs in any language, using any off the shelf UI components.&#xA;For the original, deprecated, MGM pattern which initially inspired this &amp;ldquo;MVC-App Pattern&amp;rdquo; pattern, see MGM pattern&#xA;TodoMVC-OO This is the classic Javascript TodoMVC app implemented without a framework 😄, simply using plain Object Oriented programming + a traditional MVC design pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring to PureMVC</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2009/04/01/refactoring-to-puremvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2009/04/01/refactoring-to-puremvc/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to refactor an existing architecture to the PureMVC architecture. Your application requires that you display &amp;lsquo;model&amp;rsquo; data in some sort of UI &amp;lsquo;view&amp;rsquo;.&#xA;Introduction MVC Architectural Pattern I have long been fascinated by the MVC (Model View Controller) architectural pattern, first conceived in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s. What it promises, to those who can fathom its mysteries, is an orderly way of organising your application architecture. You define a de-coupled domain/business model that is oblivious to any GUI that might be displaying it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extract Composite Refactoring</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2008/03/05/extract-composite-refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2008/03/05/extract-composite-refactoring/</guid>
      <description>Extract Composite - Refactoring to a Pattern Refactoring existing code so that it improves and conforms to a design pattern can be a good thing. Your code will be easier to understand since it follows a known &amp;lsquo;pattern&amp;rsquo;. Of course you have to need the change - your code will probably be uncomfortable to read and be crying out for clarification.&#xA;This refactoring is about implementing a one to many relationship in your code more clearly by refactoring to the Composite design pattern.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swapping Implementations</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2005/03/05/swapping-implementations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2005/03/05/swapping-implementations/</guid>
      <description>This is an exploration of how to swap implementations of objects within our software architectures using patterns like the Interface, Factory, Strategy, Proxy, Adapter, and finally to the full blown Bridge Design Pattern. This article was formerly known as The &amp;ldquo;Road to the Bridge&amp;rdquo; and as &amp;ldquo;Strategy to Bridge&amp;rdquo;&#xA;The problem We want to be flexible in our architecture. We want to be able to swap implementations of objects/classes easily e.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
