<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EuroPi - Trigger to Gate</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-trigger-to-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-trigger-to-gate/</guid>
      <description>Trigger to Gate Script for EuroPi This script allows you to convert trigger into a gate signal.&#xA;I originally wrote this script because my 2hp MIDI module clock outputs 6ms triggers, which are too short to inter-operate with most of my Eurorack modules, which require longer gates e.g. 200ms.&#xA;Using my disting module or buying a Doepfer A-162-2 Dual Trigger Delay module just for this seemed overkill, so I wrote this script for my existing EuroPi module, which at the time, did not have a trigger to gate script.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EuroPi - Utility Classes</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-script-utils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-script-utils/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My Trigger to Gate script for EuroPi uses some utility functions I developed, that might be useful for other EuroPi scripts:&#xA;KnobWithHysteresis KnobWithPassThrough Scheduler Rather than each EuroPi script inventing its own hyseresis mitigation and knob pass-through logic etc., these utility classes can be used by any EuroPi script that needs them. You can install them into the lib/contrib/experimental directory of the EuroPi software, or in a separate lib/contrib/utils directory - you can put them wherever you want, even copy and paste them into the body of your script.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
