<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calculators on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/tags/calculators/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calculators on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:43:03 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/tags/calculators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Websites</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</guid>
      <description>Being an application software developer, I made the transition to building web applications. Here are some of them.&#xA;Website Description Technology GitUML UML visualisation for Git repositories Python, Django, Javascript Python to RPN Python to RPN converter Python, Flask, Javascript RPN Calculators Online RPN calculators programmable in Javascript Javascript, HTML, CSS Toolback - App Builder An online programming environment, with low code features. Python, Javascript Chord Jammer A midi web app that lets you play chords with 1 finger in the left hand and jam safely in the right hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript RPN calculators</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rpn-calcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rpn-calcs/</guid>
      <description>These RPN calculators are programmable in Javascript, thus taking the vintage HP calculator paradigm and adding a modern language.&#xA;Rpn-calc Here is the built in Javascript code editor.&#xA;Parameters to Javascript functions are taken off the RPN stack. Return values from Javascript functions are pushed onto the RPN stack.&#xA;https://atug.com/jsrpncalc-web/&#xA;Rpn-calc2 A completely new implementation, also programmable in Javascript. Define interactive UI buttons and sliders.&#xA;https://atug.com/jsrpncalc2/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python to RPN</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/pyrpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/pyrpn/</guid>
      <description>A Python to HP42S RPN converter website www.pyrpn.atug.com Allows you to program your old vintage HP Calculator in Python!&#xA;See also my blog post How I used the Python AST capabilities to build a Python to Rpn converter.&#xA;You write code in a high level structured language (which happens to be Python 3 syntax), hit a button and RPN is generated. You then paste the RPN into Free42 or transfer it to your DM42 (by creating a raw) - and it runs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toolback</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/toolback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/toolback/</guid>
      <description>Toolback - Low Code App Builder.&#xA;An online programming environment, with low code features. Drag and drop a UI and add scripts directly to components. Generate websites and desktop apps (electron based) with a click of a button.&#xA;Toolback Toolback is the drag and drop UI builder and online, Low Code, app building IDE.&#xA;Preview your app with a key press.&#xA;Export to a website or electron app - one click!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Print42</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/print42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:18:07 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/print42/</guid>
      <description>Print42 is a log tailing GUI program which optionally echoes log lines to thermal printer tape. Its like a modern thermal printer version of a ticker tape for tailing log files. It features display font size options, search and filtering. You can also annotate the output with text fragments that you type in - or screenshots that you paste in.&#xA;As well as physically printing from Free42, the Print42 software can also be used to print HP Prime screenshots (from either the emulator or real HP Prime hardware via the HP connectivity kit).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python AST Parsing</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/python-ast-parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/python-ast-parsing/</guid>
      <description>How I used the Python AST capabilities to build the Python to Rpn converter.&#xA;Python compilation pipeline My program works at the AST stage of the compilation pipeline:&#xA;Specifically my approach has been to use Python&amp;rsquo;s built in ability to parse itself into an AST Abstract Syntax Tree, then to traverse this tree using the visitor design pattern to generate the RPN.&#xA;The Python AST parser is built into Python and thus requires that you be running Python to use it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
