<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Product on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/tags/software-product/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Product on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 18:15:42 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/tags/software-product/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dedent for Dart</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/dedent-dart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/dedent-dart/</guid>
      <description>Dedent for Dart Dedent - Remove any common leading whitespace from every line in text. Ported from Python.&#xA;https://pub.dev/packages/dedent</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron-Flask App Generator</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/electron-flask-app-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/electron-flask-app-gen/</guid>
      <description>Electron-Flask App Generator Yoeman project generator to create an Electron app running a Flask server inside itself. Deployable via PyInstaller and Electron Forge packager.&#xA;Create an Electron App project that auto-starts a Flask server the electron app can call for services. Deployable as a single App that users can double click on and run.&#xA;https://github.com/abulka/generator-electron-flask&#xA;_-----_ ╭──────────────────────────╮ | | │ Welcome to the amazing │ |--(o)--| │ generator-electron-flask │ `---------´ │ generator!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EuroPi - Trigger to Gate</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-trigger-to-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-trigger-to-gate/</guid>
      <description>Trigger to Gate Script for EuroPi This script allows you to convert trigger into a gate signal.&#xA;This is a common requirement in Eurorack modular synthesizers, where some modules require a gate signal to trigger an event, rather than a trigger signal.&#xA;See this explanation on the difference between gates and triggers.&#xA;I originally wrote this script because my 2hp MIDI module clock was outputting 6ms triggers, which are too short to inter-operate with most of my Eurorack modules, which require longer gates e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EuroPi - Andy&#39;s Utility Classes</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-script-utils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/europi-script-utils/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My Trigger to Gate script for EuroPi uses some utility functions I developed, that might be useful for other EuroPi scripts:&#xA;KnobWithHysteresis KnobWithPassThrough Scheduler Rather than each EuroPi script inventing its own hyseresis mitigation and knob pass-through logic etc., these utility classes can be used by any EuroPi script that needs them.&#xA;You can install them into the lib/contrib/experimental directory of the EuroPi software, or in a separate lib/contrib/utils directory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Image Presenter</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/image-presenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/image-presenter/</guid>
      <description>Image Presenter An image presentation tool, where you can click and zoom into various parts of a single image.&#xA;Relevant text notes associated with each sub-area would appear when zoomed in. Arrow keys/buttons allow you to step through a narrated sequence of zooms, so that you get can be carefully guided through an art image, or diagram.&#xA;Two demo prototype versions, using different underlying technologies:&#xA;https://atug.com/image_presenter/layerjs/ https://atug.com/image_presenter/zoomooz/ Source code currently unreleased.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebook Tools</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/jupyter-notebook-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/jupyter-notebook-tools/</guid>
      <description>Jupyter Notebook Tools A way of implementing complex calculators incl. scrolling text area UI widgets within Jupyter &amp;amp; Colaboratory Notebooks.&#xA;Scrolling Textareas for Jupyter Notebooks Scrolling Textareas in a Python Jupyter Notebook, allows building a kind of &amp;ldquo;Calculator Playground&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Various Jupyter Notebooks at https://bitbucket.org/abulka/jupyter_play/src/master/ (private)&#xA;Gist of the scrolling textarea technique: https://gist.github.com/abulka/3043e8a4d78d2e26f872542524a0aa3e (public)&#xA;Google Colaboratory A way of implementing UI scrolling regions within Google Colaboratory Notebooks. Google Colaboratory, or &amp;ldquo;Colab&amp;rdquo; for short, is a version of Jupyter Notebooks, and allows you to write and execute Python in your browser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libraries &amp; Tools</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/</guid>
      <description>Here are some of the libraries and tools I have created:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relationship Manager for Python 3</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/relationship-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/relationship-manager/</guid>
      <description>Relationship Manager A lightweight Object Database (no SQL used) class for Python 3&#xA;https://pypi.org/project/relationship-manager/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snippet Creator</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippet-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippet-creator/</guid>
      <description>Snippet Creator This Visual Studio Code extension helps to automate snippet creation. Select the code you want to create snippet from and use command Create Snippet from the command palette or your custom keybind.&#xA;https://github.com/abulka/vscode-snippet-creator</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snippets Explorer</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippets-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/libraries/snippets-explorer/</guid>
      <description>Snippets Explorer Visual Studio Code extension which displays all available language snippets in a TreeView&#xA;https://github.com/abulka/vscode-snippets-explorer</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Websites</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</guid>
      <description>Being an application software developer, I made the transition to building web applications. Here are some of them.&#xA;Website Description Technology GitUML UML visualisation for Git repositories Python, Django, Javascript Python to RPN Python to RPN converter Python, Flask, Javascript RPN Calculators Online RPN calculators programmable in Javascript Javascript, HTML, CSS Toolback - App Builder An online programming environment, with low code features. Python, Javascript Chord Jammer A midi web app that lets you play chords with 1 finger in the left hand and jam safely in the right hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chord Jammer</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/chordjammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/chordjammer/</guid>
      <description>A midi web app that lets you play chords with 1 finger in the left hand and jam safely in the right hand. As you change chords, the rh notes are filtered so you always play good sounding notes.&#xA;Try it out at Chord Jammer&#xA;Code&#xA;~/Devel/midi-play/webmidijs-play Sample config export let project = { chords: { &amp;#39;C3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: Em7Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleMelodic, }, &amp;#39;D3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: AmAdd9Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, }, &amp;#39;E3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: CM9Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, }, &amp;#39;F3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: BmAdd11ChordInversion1, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, rhnotes2: EmScaleHarmonic, rhnotes3: EmBlues, } } } Single finger Chords With the project config above</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitUML</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/gituml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/gituml/</guid>
      <description>UML visualisation for Git repositories (website app).&#xA;Understand code quickly: Automatically generate UML class diagrams from source code residing in git repositories. Diagrams automatically update when you push code using git.&#xA;Visit GitUML now, create a free account and begin creating UML diagrams and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript RPN calculators</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rpn-calcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rpn-calcs/</guid>
      <description>These RPN calculators are programmable in Javascript, thus taking the vintage HP calculator paradigm and adding a modern language.&#xA;Rpn-calc Here is the built in Javascript code editor.&#xA;Parameters to Javascript functions are taken off the RPN stack. Return values from Javascript functions are pushed onto the RPN stack.&#xA;https://atug.com/jsrpncalc-web/&#xA;Rpn-calc2 A completely new implementation, also programmable in Javascript. Define interactive UI buttons and sliders.&#xA;https://atug.com/jsrpncalc2/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pynsource</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/pynsource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/pynsource/</guid>
      <description>Visit pynsource.com.&#xA;Pynsource is a UML tool for Python a desktop App for Mac, Window and Linux.&#xA;Pynsource imports Python code and features zoom, Ascii and PlantUML views and Auto Layout&#xA;Community Edition is free, fully functional and open source - check out the Pynsource GitHub repository.&#xA;Buy the Pro Edition for $20 to unlock the zoom feature and other pro features.&#xA;Visit the Pynsource Home Page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python to RPN</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/pyrpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/pyrpn/</guid>
      <description>A Python to HP42S RPN converter website www.pyrpn.atug.com Allows you to program your old vintage HP Calculator in Python!&#xA;See also my blog post How I used the Python AST capabilities to build a Python to Rpn converter.&#xA;You write code in a high level structured language (which happens to be Python 3 syntax), hit a button and RPN is generated. You then paste the RPN into Free42 or transfer it to your DM42 (by creating a raw) - and it runs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toolback</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/toolback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/toolback/</guid>
      <description>Toolback - Low Code App Builder.&#xA;An online programming environment, with low code features. Drag and drop a UI and add scripts directly to components. Generate websites and desktop apps (electron based) with a click of a button.&#xA;Toolback Toolback is the drag and drop UI builder and online, Low Code, app building IDE.&#xA;Preview your app with a key press.&#xA;Export to a website or electron app - one click!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Image Browser</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/ai-images-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:21:55 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/ai-images-manager/</guid>
      <description>AI Image Browser This program is designed to make it easier to browse and delete the images generated by Stable Diffusion AI image generators.&#xA;Click on an image to preview it, and view the &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; text which generated it. Hit &amp;lsquo;Delete&amp;rsquo; to delete an unwanted image (and its associated .text or .yml file). For a full list of features see the home page.&#xA;See homepage https://ai-image-browser.firebaseapp.com/&#xA;Status Free to download and try - option to upgrade to paid version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brew Moments</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/brew-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:21:55 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/brew-moments/</guid>
      <description>Brew Moments Coffee Ratio Calculation App for Android phones and tablets, built using Dart and Flutter.&#xA;Visit the Brew Moments home page Visit the Brew Moments playstore page Status Free to download.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Print42</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/print42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:18:07 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/print42/</guid>
      <description>Print42 is a log tailing GUI program which optionally echoes log lines to thermal printer tape. Its like a modern thermal printer version of a ticker tape for tailing log files. It features display font size options, search and filtering. You can also annotate the output with text fragments that you type in - or screenshots that you paste in.&#xA;As well as physically printing from Free42, the Print42 software can also be used to print HP Prime screenshots (from either the emulator or real HP Prime hardware via the HP connectivity kit).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prophet 6 Librarian</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/prophet-6-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/prophet-6-librarian/</guid>
      <description>Midi patch converter and patch librarian for the Prophet 6 synthesizer.&#xA;Features listens for sysex messages from prophet 6 records them in a list, marked as &amp;lsquo;raw&amp;rsquo; click a button (or perhaps its done automatically) and convert them into &amp;lsquo;audition&amp;rsquo; style click on either raw or audition button to send patch back to the prophet 6 UI of the Prophet 6 knobs and buttons (as pictured) adjusts patches in real time Status Unreleased, on hold.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
