<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:43:03 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Websites</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</guid>
      <description>Being an application software developer, I made the transition to building web applications. Here are some of them.&#xA;Website Description Technology GitUML UML visualisation for Git repositories Python, Django, Javascript Python to RPN Python to RPN converter Python, Flask, Javascript RPN Calculators Online RPN calculators programmable in Javascript Javascript, HTML, CSS Toolback - App Builder An online programming environment, with low code features. Python, Javascript Chord Jammer A midi web app that lets you play chords with 1 finger in the left hand and jam safely in the right hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chord Jammer</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/chordjammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/chordjammer/</guid>
      <description>A midi web app that lets you play chords with 1 finger in the left hand and jam safely in the right hand. As you change chords, the rh notes are filtered so you always play good sounding notes.&#xA;Try it out at Chord Jammer&#xA;Code&#xA;~/Devel/midi-play/webmidijs-play Sample config export let project = { chords: { &amp;#39;C3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: Em7Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleMelodic, }, &amp;#39;D3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: AmAdd9Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, }, &amp;#39;E3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: CM9Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, }, &amp;#39;F3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: BmAdd11ChordInversion1, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, rhnotes2: EmScaleHarmonic, rhnotes3: EmBlues, } } } Single finger Chords With the project config above</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prophet 6 Librarian</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/prophet-6-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/prophet-6-librarian/</guid>
      <description>Midi patch converter and patch librarian for the Prophet 6 synthesizer.&#xA;Features listens for sysex messages from prophet 6 records them in a list, marked as &amp;lsquo;raw&amp;rsquo; click a button (or perhaps its done automatically) and convert them into &amp;lsquo;audition&amp;rsquo; style click on either raw or audition button to send patch back to the prophet 6 UI of the Prophet 6 knobs and buttons (as pictured) adjusts patches in real time Status Unreleased, on hold.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
