<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Websites on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Websites on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chord Jammer</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/chordjammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/chordjammer/</guid>
      <description>A midi web app that lets you play chords with 1 finger in the left hand and jam safely in the right hand. As you change chords, the rh notes are filtered so you always play good sounding notes.&#xA;Try it out at Chord Jammer&#xA;Code&#xA;~/Devel/midi-play/webmidijs-play Sample config export let project = { chords: { &amp;#39;C3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: Em7Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleMelodic, }, &amp;#39;D3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: AmAdd9Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, }, &amp;#39;E3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: CM9Chord, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, }, &amp;#39;F3&amp;#39;: { lhchord: BmAdd11ChordInversion1, rhnotes: EmScaleNatural, rhnotes2: EmScaleHarmonic, rhnotes3: EmBlues, } } } Single finger Chords With the project config above</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitUML</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/gituml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/gituml/</guid>
      <description>UML visualisation for Git repositories (website app).&#xA;Understand code quickly: Automatically generate UML class diagrams from source code residing in git repositories. Diagrams automatically update when you push code using git.&#xA;Visit GitUML now, create a free account and begin creating UML diagrams and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript RPN calculators</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rpn-calcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rpn-calcs/</guid>
      <description>These RPN calculators are programmable in Javascript, thus taking the vintage HP calculator paradigm and adding a modern language.&#xA;Rpn-calc Here is the built in Javascript code editor.&#xA;Parameters to Javascript functions are taken off the RPN stack. Return values from Javascript functions are pushed onto the RPN stack.&#xA;https://atug.com/jsrpncalc-web/&#xA;Rpn-calc2 A completely new implementation, also programmable in Javascript. Define interactive UI buttons and sliders.&#xA;https://atug.com/jsrpncalc2/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python to RPN</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/pyrpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/pyrpn/</guid>
      <description>A Python to HP42S RPN converter website www.pyrpn.atug.com Allows you to program your old vintage HP Calculator in Python!&#xA;See also my blog post How I used the Python AST capabilities to build a Python to Rpn converter.&#xA;You write code in a high level structured language (which happens to be Python 3 syntax), hit a button and RPN is generated. You then paste the RPN into Free42 or transfer it to your DM42 (by creating a raw) - and it runs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationale</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rationale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/rationale/</guid>
      <description>As CTO of Austhink, I technically managed and helped architect Rationale - an argument mapping application, written in C# and .NET. This was done together with a great team of developers and thinkers incl. the CEO Tim van Gelder.&#xA;Rationale - the desktop app&#xA;Rationale is now available as an online web app at https://www.rationaleonline.com/&#xA;🎗 Disclaimer: The web version of Rationale was developed by another team, using the source code and design of the desktop Rationale as a base.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toolback</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/toolback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/websites/toolback/</guid>
      <description>Toolback - Low Code App Builder.&#xA;An online programming environment, with low code features. Drag and drop a UI and add scripts directly to components. Generate websites and desktop apps (electron based) with a click of a button.&#xA;Toolback Toolback is the drag and drop UI builder and online, Low Code, app building IDE.&#xA;Preview your app with a key press.&#xA;Export to a website or electron app - one click!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
