<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apps on Andy Bulka</title>
    <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apps on Andy Bulka</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pynsource</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/pynsource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/pynsource/</guid>
      <description>Visit pynsource.com.&#xA;Pynsource is a UML tool for Python a desktop App for Mac, Window and Linux.&#xA;Pynsource imports Python code and features zoom, Ascii and PlantUML views and Auto Layout&#xA;Community Edition is free, fully functional and open source - check out the Pynsource GitHub repository.&#xA;Buy the Pro Edition for $20 to unlock the zoom feature and other pro features.&#xA;Visit the Pynsource Home Page</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Image Browser</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/ai-images-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:21:55 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/ai-images-manager/</guid>
      <description>AI Image Browser This program is designed to make it easier to browse and delete the images generated by Stable Diffusion AI image generators.&#xA;Click on an image to preview it, and view the &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; text which generated it. Hit &amp;lsquo;Delete&amp;rsquo; to delete an unwanted image (and its associated .text or .yml file). For a full list of features see the home page.&#xA;See homepage https://ai-image-browser.firebaseapp.com/&#xA;Status Free to download and try - option to upgrade to paid version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brew Moments</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/brew-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:21:55 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/brew-moments/</guid>
      <description>Brew Moments Coffee Ratio Calculation App for Android phones and tablets, built using Dart and Flutter.&#xA;Visit the Brew Moments home page Visit the Brew Moments playstore page Status Free to download.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Print42</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/print42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:18:07 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/print42/</guid>
      <description>Print42 is a log tailing GUI program which optionally echoes log lines to thermal printer tape. Its like a modern thermal printer version of a ticker tape for tailing log files. It features display font size options, search and filtering. You can also annotate the output with text fragments that you type in - or screenshots that you paste in.&#xA;As well as physically printing from Free42, the Print42 software can also be used to print HP Prime screenshots (from either the emulator or real HP Prime hardware via the HP connectivity kit).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prophet 6 Librarian</title>
      <link>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/prophet-6-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abulka.github.io/projects/apps/prophet-6-librarian/</guid>
      <description>Midi patch converter and patch librarian for the Prophet 6 synthesizer.&#xA;Features listens for sysex messages from prophet 6 records them in a list, marked as &amp;lsquo;raw&amp;rsquo; click a button (or perhaps its done automatically) and convert them into &amp;lsquo;audition&amp;rsquo; style click on either raw or audition button to send patch back to the prophet 6 UI of the Prophet 6 knobs and buttons (as pictured) adjusts patches in real time Status Unreleased, on hold.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
